Hartford Voter Registration Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Hartford Voter Registration Records.
1840-1986.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Reserch Center.
Hartford Registrar of Voters.
261 linear feet.
MSS19890055
The office of the Registrar of Voters was established in the early 1860s. The office is responsible for registering voters, the voting machines, polling place, and absentee balloting.
History
The Office of the Registrar of Voters was established in the early 1860s. The Registrar is an elected position. One Democrat and one Republican Registrar is elected to represent their respective party. The office is responsible for registering voters, the voting machines, polling place, and absentee balloting. When voting is complete, the office, in conjunction with a duly appointed moderator, compiles and tallies the votes. Once this has been done, the moderator sends a copy of the results to the Secretary of State and to the Town Clerk.
Scope and Content
The Voter Registration Records contain checklists of voters and voter registration cards from the City of Hartford. The cards contain some or all of the following personal information on registered voters: name, residence (including address changes within the city), caucus and party affiliation, ward number, date individual became eligible to vote, place and date of birth, dates of continuous residence, occupation and employer, sex, marital status, and naturalization data.
Arrangement
Series I: Checklists of Voters ( 1840-1951 ) consists of 189 bound volumes. Each volume lists the electors eligible to vote in that election. The lists were prepared by the Registrar of Voters and are organized by ward, precinct, street name (in alphabetical order) and address. The volumes are organized chronologically.
Series II: Hartford Voter Registration Cards ( 1916-1986 ) are organized by the date the individual became ineligible to vote; within the “off-dates” the cards are filed alphabetically. The cards include some or all of the following information: name, residence (including address changes within the city), caucus and party affiliation, ward number, date individual became eligible to vote, place and date of birth, dates of continuous residence, occupation and employer, sex, marital status, and naturalization data. The cards are arranged in three alphabetical sequences prior to 1969. The first sequence dates from 1916-66, with bulk dates of 1922-34. The second sequence dates from 1926-1968, with bulk dates of 1935-65. The third sequence is not dated but appears to date from the 1960s. Following these three alphabetical sequences, the cards are arranged alphabetically within each year, 1969-84.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Voting—Connecticut.; Voter registration—Connecticut.; Connecticut—Voting registers.; Hartford (Conn.)—Voting registers.; Connecticut—Politics and government.; Hartford (Conn.)—Politics and government.; Connecticut—Vital records.; Hartford (Conn.)—Vital records.
Document Types:
Checklists.; Administrative Records.
Occupations:
Municipal office.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The Hartford Voter Registration Records were transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives division (now Archives and Special Collections) as part of the Peoples of Connecticut Ethnic Heritage Project in August 1979. Hartford Voter Registration cards from 1981, 1982, and 1983 were transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives in January, 1989; cards from 1984 were transferred in June, 1990.
Acquisition Information
The Hartford Voter Registration Records were transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives division (now Archives and Special Collections) as part of the Peoples of Connecticut Ethnic Heritage Project in August 1979. Hartford Voter Registration cards from 1981, 1982, and 1983 were transferred to Historical Manuscripts and Archives in January, 1989; cards from 1984 were transferred in June, 1990.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Checklists of Voters, 1840-1951
  - 1840 April (Volume 1)
  - 1840 November (Volume 2)
  - 1841 April (Volume 3)
  - 1842 April (Volume 4)
  - 1842 November (Volume 5)
  - 1843 May (Volume 6)
  - 1843 November (Volume 7)
  - 1844 November (Volume 8)
  - 1845 April (Volume 9)
  - 1845 October (Volume 10)
  - 1845 November (Volume 11)
  - 1846 April (Volume 12)
  - 1846 November (Volume 13)
  - 1847 April (Volume 14)
  - 1847 October (Volume 15)
  - 1847 November (Volume 16)
  - 1848 April (Volume 17)
  - 1848 November (Volume 18)
  - 1849 April (Volume 19)
  - 1849 November (Volume 20)
  - 1850 April (Volume 21)
  - 1850 April (Volume 22)
  - 1850 November (Volume 23)
  - 1851 April (Volume 24)
  - 1851 November (Volume 25)
  - 1852 April (Volume 26)
  - 1852 November (Volume 27)
  - 1852 November (Volume 28)
  - 1853 April (Volume 29)
  - 1853 April (Volume 30)
  - 1854 April (Volume 31)
  - 1854 April (Volume 32)
  - 1854 July (Volume 33)
  - 1854 August (Volume 34)
  - 1854 November (Volume 35)
  - 1855 April (Volume 36)
  - 1855 April (Volume 37)
  - 1855 October (Volume 38)
  - 1855 November (Volume 39)
  - 1856 April (Volume 40)
  - 1856 November, Presidential Election (Volume 41)
  - 1856 November, Town Meeting (Volume 42)
  - 1857 April (Volume 43)
  - 1857 November (Volume 44)
  - 1864 April (Volume 45)
  - 1864 August (Volume 46)
  - 1864 November, Presidential Election (Volume 47)
  - 1864 November, Town Election (Volume 48)
  - 1865 April (Volume 49)
  - 1865 October (Volume 50)
  - 1867 April (Volume 51)
  - 1867 November (Volume 52)
  - 1868 October (Volume 53)
  - 1868 November (Volume 54)
  - 1869 April (Volume 55)
  - 1869 October (Volume 56)
  - 1870 April (Volume 57)
  - 1870 October (Volume 58)
  - 1871 April (Volume 59)
  - 1871 October (Volume 60)
  - 1872 April (Volume 61)
  - 1872 October (Volume 62)
  - 1872 November (Volume 63)
  - 1873 April (Volume 64)
  - 1873 April (Volume 65)
  - 1875 April (Volume 66)
  - 1875 October (Volume 67)
  - 1876 April (Volume 68)
  - 1876 October (Volume 69)
  - 1876 November (Volume 70)
  - 1877 October (Volume 71)
  - 1877 November (Volume 72)
  - 1878 October (Volume 73)
  - 1878 November (Volume 74)
  - 1879 October (Volume 75)
  - 1879 November (Volume 76)
  - 1880 October (Volume 77)
  - 1880 November (Volume 78)
  - 1881 October (Volume 79)
  - 1881 November (Volume 80)
  - 1882 October (Volume 81)
  - 1882 November (Volume 82)
  - 1883 October (Volume 83)
  - 1883 November (Volume 84)
  - 1884 October (Volume 85)
  - 1884 November (Volume 86)
  - 1885 April (Volume 87)
  - 1885 October (Volume 88)
  - 1885 November (Volume 89)
  - 1886 April (Volume 90)
  - 1886 October (Volume 91)
  - 1886 November (Volume 92)
  - 1888 April (Volume 93)
  - 1888 October (Volume 94)
  - 1888 November (Volume 95)
  - 1889 April (Volume 96)
  - 1889 October (Volume 97)
  - 1890 April (Volume 98)
  - 1890 November (Volume 99)
  - 1891 April (Volume 100)
  - 1891 October (Volume 101)
  - 1892 April (Volume 102)
  - 1892 October (Volume 103)
  - 1893 April (Volume 104)
  - 1893 October (Volume 105)
  - 1894 April (Volume 106)
  - 1894 October (Volume 107)
  - 1894 November (Volume 108)
  - 1895 April (Volume 109)
  - 1895 October (Volume 110)
  - 1896 April (Volume 111)
  - 1896 October (Volume 112)
  - 1897 October (Volume 113)
  - 1898 April (Volume 114)
  - 1898 November (Volume 115)
  - 1899 April (Volume 116)
  - 1900 April (Volume 117)
  - 1900 November (Volume 118)
  - 1901 April (Volume 119)
  - 1901 October (Volume 120)
  - 1901 November (Volume 121)
  - 1902 April (Volume 122)
  - 1902 June (Volume 123)
  - 1902 November (Volume 124)
  - 1903 April (Volume 125)
  - 1904 April (Volume 126)
  - 1904 November (Volume 127)
  - 1905 April (Volume 128)
  - 1905 October (Volume 129)
  - 1906 April (Volume 130)
  - 1906 November (Volume 131)
  - 1907 April (Volume 132)
  - 1907 October (Volume 133)
  - 1908 April (Volume 134)
  - 1908 November (Volume 135)
  - 1909 April (Volume 136)
  - 1910 April (Volume 137)
  - 1910 November (Volume 138)
  - 1911 April (Volume 139)
  - 1912 April (Volume 140)
  - 1912 November (Volume 141)
  - 1913 April (Volume 142)
  - 1913 October (Volume 143)
  - 1914 April (Volume 144)
  - 1914 November (Volume 145)
  - 1915 April (Volume 146)
  - 1916 April (Volume 147)
  - 1916 November (Volume 148)
  - 1916 April (Volume 149)
  - 1918 April (Volume 150)
  - 1918 (Volume 151)
  - 1919 April (Volume 152)
  - 1920 April (Volume 153)
  - Women Voters, 1920 April (Volume 154)
  - 1920 November (Volume 155)
  - 1921 April (Volume 156)
  - 1921 June (Volume 157)
  - 1922 April (Volume 158)
  - 1922 November (Volume 159)
  - 1923 April (Volume 160)
  - 1924 April (Volume 161)
  - 1924 November (Volume 162)
  - 1924 December (Volume 163)
  - 1925 April (Volume 164)
  - 1926 April (Volume 165)
  - 1926 November (Volume 166)
  - 1927 April (Volume 167)
  - 1928 April (Volume 168)
  - 1928 November (Volume 169)
  - 1929 November (Volume 170)
  - 1930 November (Volume 171)
  - 1931 November (Volume 172)
  - 1932 November (Volume 173)
  - 1933 June (Volume 174)
  - 1933 November (Volume 175)
  - 1934 November (Volume 176)
  - 1935 November (Volume 177)
  - 1936 November (Volume 178)
  - 1937 November (Volume 179)
  - 1938 November (Volume 180)
  - 1939 November (Volume 181)
  - 1940 November (Volume 182)
  - 1941 November (Volume 183)
  - 1942 November (Volume 184)
  - 1948 November (Volume 185)
  - 1949 November (Volume 186)
  - 1950 November (Volume 187)
  - 1951 October (Volume 188)
  - 1951 November (Volume 189)
- Series II: Hartford Voter Registration Cards, undated, 1916-1986
  - Cabinet
    - 1916-1966
      - A — D (Othertype 1)
      - D — Z (Othertype 2)
    - 1926-1968
      - A — Er (Othertype 3)
      - Es — Kuz (Othertype 4)
      - Kv — Reh (Othertype 5)
      - Re — Wo (Othertype 6)
    - 1969
      - Aag — Allen, C (Box 190)
      - Allen, C — Andrian, F (Box 191)
      - Andrian, G — Ashmore, A (Box 192)
      - Ashmore, E — Bab (Box 193)
      - Bac — Bane, M (Box 194)
      - Bane, W — Bar (Box 195)
      - Bas — Bell, D (Box 196)
      - Bell, E — Bertsche (Box 197)
      - Bertschy — Boccacio A (Box 198)
      - Boccacio, E -Bough (Box 199)
      - Bougi — Bright, Marj (Box 200)
      - Bright, Mart — Budne (Box 201)
      - Budni — Caldwell, H (Box 202)
      - Caldwell, J — Caro (Box 203)
      - Carp — Cet (Box 204)
      - Cha — Cianci, Sal (Box 205)
      - Cianci, Sam — Cohen (Box 206)
      - Cohens — Corcoran, P (Box 207)
      - Corcoran, R — Crane (Box 208)
      - Crank — Dahlin, L (Box 209)
      - Dahlin, M — Da (Box 210)
      - De — DeVeau, Ro (Box 211)
      - DeVeau, Ru — D'Onof (Box 212)
      - Donog — Duncan, Ge (Box 213)
      - Duncan, Go — Enders, E (Box 214)
      - Enders, T — Feliciano, J (Box 215)
      - Feliciano, M — Fogarty, M (Box 216)
      - Fogarty, P — Free (Box 217)
      - Fren — Gardner, G (Box 218)
      - Gardner, I — Gilbert, U (Box 219)
      - Gilbert, W — Goe (Box 220)
      - Gof — Grana (Box 221)
      - Grand — Guil (Box 222)
      - Guim — Harris, Ed (Box 223)
      - Harris, Es — Herm (Box 224)
      - Hern — Hoo (Box 225)
      - Hor — I (Box 226)
      - J — Johnson, Pe (Box 227)
      - Johnson, Ph — Karotkin, A (Box 228)
      - Karotkin, C — Khoo (Box 229)
      - Kib — Koz (Box 230)
      - Kra — Lal (Box 231)
      - LaM — LaVoie, Herb (Box 232)
      - LaVoie, Herv — Leon (Box 233)
      - Leop — Livec (Box 234)
      - Liver — Ly (Box 235)
      - M — Mam (Box 236)
      - Man — Marti (Box 237)
      - Marto — McCork (Box 238)
      - McCorm — McQ (Box 239)
      - McR — Miller, Howard D (Box 240)
      - Miller, Howard L — Morea, A (Box 241)
      - Morea, C — Murning, J (Box 242)
      - Murning, R — Newton, D (Box 243)
      - Newton, E — O'Hara, F (Box 244)
      - O'Hara, J — Palazzi (Box 245)
      - Palazzo — Parl (Box 246)
      - Parm — Pfeif (Box 247)
      - Pfeil — Pomerleau, A (Box 248)
      - Pomerleau, J-Q (Box 249)
      - R — Rett (Box 250)
      - Rettm — Robinson, Al (Box 251)
      - Robinson, An — Rossa (Box 252)
      - Rossb — Sah (Box 253)
      - Sal — Schm (Box 254)
      - Schn — Shea, B (Box 255)
      - Shea, C — Simpson, L (Box 256)
      - Simpson, M — Smith, Ron (Box 257)
      - Smith, Ros — Stanton, Ri (Box 258)
      - Stanton, Ru — Str (Box 259)
      - St. C — Sve (Box 260)
      - T — Til (Box 261)
      - Tho — Tulin, A (Box 262)
      - Tilin, B — Vero (Box 263)
      - Verr — Wardl (Box 264)
      - Wardr — We (Box 265)
      - Wh — Winick, L (Box 266)
      - Winick, M — Young, D (Box 267)
      - Young, E — Z (Box 268)
      - A — Flannery, H (Box 269)
      - Flannery, J — Halli (Box 270)
      - Hallo — Ken (Box 271)
      - Kin — Lyt (Box 272)
      - Man — Nol (Box 273)
      - Nor — Rez (Box 274)
      - Rho — Silvei (Box 275)
      - Silver — Thompson, R (Box 276)
      - Thompson, S — Z (Box 277)
    - 1970
      - A — Davis, Margaret L (Box 278)
      - Davis, Margaret M — Gonsalves, A (Box 279)
      - Gonsalves, F — Lefeb (Box 280)
      - Lefel — Niel (Box 281)
      - Niev — Valentin (Box 282)
      - Valentine — Z (Box 283)
    - 1971
      - Bro — Comeau, H (Box 284)
      - Comeau, J — Duc (Box 285)
      - Dud — Gitlin, E (Box 286)
      - Gitlin, N — Horton, C (Box 287)
      - Horton, F — LaVoie, Ch (Box 288)
      - LaVoie, Cl — McGrath, A (Box 289)
      - McGrath, E — Parker, M (Box 290)
      - Parker, P — Rot (Box 291)
      - Rou — Stid (Box 292)
      - Stig — Wet (Box 293)
      - Wey — Z (Box 294)
    - 1972
      - A — Bouf (Box 295)
      - Boul — Clare (Box 296)
      - Clark — Doy (Box 297)
      - Dra — Fut (Box 298)
      - Gab — G (Box 299)
      - H — Joi (Box 300)
      - Jon — Lem (Box 301)
      - Len — Meb (Box 302)
      - Med — Ol (Box 303)
      - Om — Q (Box 304)
      - R (Box 305)
      - S — Sp (Box 306)
      - St — Vel (Box 307)
      - Ver — Z (Box 308)
    - 1973
      - A — Bouc (Box 309)
      - Boul — Conroy, A (Box 310)
      - Conroy, M — Dod (Box 311)
      - Doh — Garaf (Box 312)
      - Garay — Herl (Box 313)
      - Hern — Kou (Box 314)
      - Kov — Marine (Box 315)
      - Marino — M (Box 316)
      - N — Prin (Box 317)
      - Priv — Schee (Box 318)
      - Schel — Thoma (Box 319)
      - Thomp — Z (Box 320)
    - 1974
      - A — Bre (Box 321)
      - Bri — Con (Box 322)
      - Coo — Done (Box 323)
      - Donn — Gaz (Box 324)
      - Gea — Hi (Box 325)
      - Ho — Kni (Box 326)
      - Kno — Map (Box 327)
      - Mar — M (Box 328)
      - N — Po (Box 329)
      - Pr — R (Box 330)
      - Sab — Sr (Box 331)
      - St — Walka (Box 332)
      - Walke — Z (Box 333)
    - 1975
      - A — Broc (Box 334)
      - Brod — Daw (Box 335)
      - Day — Ga (Box 336)
      - Ge — Ji (Box 337)
      - Jo — L (Box 338)
      - M — N (Box 339)
      - O — Roc (Box 340)
      - Rod — St (Box 341)
      - Su — Z (Box 342)
    - 1976
      - A — Bradl (Box 343)
      - Brady — Delvecchio, E (Box 344)
      - Delvecchio, G — Gay (Box 345)
      - Gee — Ji (Box 346)
      - Jo — Mald (Box 347)
      - Mall — Paci (Box 348)
      - Pack — R (Box 349)
      - S — Tog (Box 350)
      - Tol — Z (Box 351)
    - 1977
      - A — Cag (Box 352)
      - Cah — Diaz, Jor (Box 353)
      - Diaz, Jos — Glym (Box 354)
      - Glyn — Jud (Box 355)
      - Jug — Manl (Box 356)
      - Mann — Owens, B (Box 357)
      - Owens, D — Ros (Box 358)
      - Rot — Tof (Box 359)
      - Tol — Z (Box 360)
    - 1978
      - A — B (Box 361)
      - C — D (Box 362)
      - De — Ga (Box 363)
      - Ge — Iw (Box 364)
      - Ja — Li (Box 365)
      - Lo — M (Box 366)
      - N — Ri (Box 367)
      - Ro — So (Box 368)
      - Sp — Z (Box 369)
    - 1979
      - A — Cha (Box 370)
      - Che — Fi (Box 371)
      - Fl — Ji (Box 372)
      - Jo — McM (Box 373)
      - McN — Richard, L (Box 374)
      - Richard, M — Ti (Box 375)
      - To — Z (Box 376)
    - 1980
      - A — Che (Box 377)
      - Chi — Fi (Box 378)
      - Fl — K (Box 379)
      - L — M (Box 380)
      - N — Roq (Box 381)
      - Ros — To (Box 382)
      - Tr — Z (Box 383)
    - 1981
      - A — Ch (Box 384)
      - Ci — E (Box 385)
      - F — His (Box 386)
      - Hit — Le (Box 387)
      - Li — Nuc (Box 388)
      - Nun — Sanc (Box 389)
      - Weis — Z (Box 391)
      - Sand — Weir (Box 390)
    - 1982
      - A — Cha (Box 392)
      - Che — Fo (Box 393)
      - Fr — Kem (Box 394)
      - Ken — Miranda, F (Box 395)
      - Miranda, M — Rod (Box 396)
      - Roe — Z (Box 397)
    - 1983
      - A — C (Box 398)
      - D — G (Box 399)
      - H — Map (Box 400)
      - Mar — Re (Box 401)
      - Rh — V (Box 402)
      - W — Z (Box 403)
    - Dates Unknown
      - Abel — Aldric (Box 404)
      - Aldrid — Austin (Box 405)
      - Allen — Wynn (Box 406)
      - Aarons — Thiel (Box 407)
      - Ackerman — Bain (Box 408)
    - 1984
      - A — Cros (Box 409)
      - Crot — Ho (Box 410)
      - Hu — O (Box 411)
      - P — S (Box 412)
      - T — Z (Box 413)
    - 1985
      - A — Day (Box 414)
      - Dean — Gwynn (Box 415)
      - H — Maz (Box 416)
      - McC — Ran (Box 417)
      - Rap — Stenger (Box 418)
      - Stephens — Z (Box 419)
    - 1986
      - A — Copeland (Box 420)
      - Cor — Gay (Box 421)
      - Gen — King (Box 422)
      - King — McW (Box 423)
      - Meade — Ritter (Box 424)
      - Rivera — Sz (Box 425)
      - Ta — Z (Box 426)